지난 회 엘리멘터리...
Previously on Elementary...
You ruined my life.
Gun!
WOMAN: A blood clot got wedged in his
right subclavian artery,
A blood clot got wedged in his
obstructed the blood flow
to his arm for about 30 minutes.
He may never regain
full use of the limb.
WATSON:
This is about your guilt.
You're not directly responsible
for what happened.
But this time your fondness
for blowing past
bureaucratic guideposts
got a man you respect shot.
You may very well
have saved my life.
I'd rather not
see you around here.
이것 보게나, 왼손잡이
Look at you, southpaw.
삶이 바뀌었잖아요?
Well, life has changed, right?
적어도 요즘에 대부분
서류 작업은 컴퓨터로 해요
At least nowadays most of
the paperwork's on the computer.
전자렌지 조리용 저녁을
만들어 봤어요
Well, I made you some
ready-to-nuke dinners.
구미 당길 요리는 아녜요
Nothing fancy.
제 요리기술 수준이
Baked ziti's about the extent
오븐구이 지티(ziti)에 정도라
of my culinary skills.
고마워요
Thanks.
정말 친절하군요
That's really nice of you.
의사가 손은 뭐래요?
What did the doctor
say about your hand?
모른답니다
Uh, he doesn't know.
아직 몇 주 밖에 안 되어서
It's only been a few weeks.
물리치료가 도움이 되긴 하지만
Physical therapy's helping,
손상이 영구적인지
but they still can't tell me
여전히 감이 안 잡히나 봐요
if the damage is permanent.
일에 복귀는 했죠
그건 좋은 일이죠
Well, you're back at
work, that's good.
예
Yeah.
일관련해서 사무 작업을, 어
일이라고 부른다면야-
If you call, uh,
pushing papers around work.
사람들이 다른 쪽 손으로
쓰는 법을 배우는 일이
Hey, you know they say
that learning to write
머리에 좋답니다
with your other hand is
good for the brain.
새로운 회로가 생겨서
젊음을 유지한대요
Builds new pathways,
keeps you young.
훌륭하군요
Great.
그러니 이 손상이 영원히
얼쩡거리고 안 없어지면
So if this, uh, trauma
sticks around forever,
저는 진짜 아주 오랫동안
즐기겠군요
I'll have a really
long time to enjoy it.
마커스 누군가 다른 사람하고...
Marcus, do you think you...
이야기를 나눠봐야겠다는
생각 없어요?
need to talk to someone?
아니요, 솔직히, 제게 진짜
필요한 일은
No, honestly, I think
what I really need
말을 더 적게 하는 겁니다
is to talk less.
챙겨줘서 다시 한 번 고마워요
Thanks again for the food.
오케이?
Okay?
알았어요, 나중에 봐요
All right, I'll see you later.
음흠
Mm-hmm.
근접각 센서 돌리지 마세요
Don't trip the proximity sensor.
저기, 실례지만 두 걸음만 물러나
주시겠습니까?
Actually, would you mind
stepping back a couple of paces?
너무 북적대는 느낌이
조금 들어서요
I'm feeling
a little bit crowded.
(-)
어이!
Hey!
미쳤어요?
Are you crazy?
오십만 달러 차라고요
That's a half-million dollar car.
Surely when
고용주가 보안조치 테스트를
위해 당신을 고용할 때는, 분명
your employers hired you
to test the security measures
조금 닳고 부서지는 결과는
감안했을 겁니다
they knew it would result in
a little bit of wear and tear.
문에 발자국 설명으론
부족할 텐데요
Wouldn't explain
a foot in the door.
그 사람들은 흡족할 일이죠
Well, they should
be pleased.
그들 시스템이
난공불락인 셈이니
Their system's
obviously impregnable.
실은, 완전 허점투성이에요
Actually,
it's totally pregnable.
오늘만도 열번은
따고 들어갔어요
I beat it ten times today.
마음이 복잡하군요
You got a lot on your mind.
당신 친구, 그 형사에게
일어난 그 일로 온통,
All the stuff that happened
with your buddy, the detective.
차에 몰래 잠입하는 일과는
완전히 상관없어요
Is utterly irrelevant
to breaking into a car.
딱 봐도 그런데
Obviously.
벨 형사의 부상을
낳은 사건의
In terms of my actions
on the case
내 행동이라는 측면에
which resulted
in Detective Bell's injury,
저는 전적으로 옳았습니다
I was completely in the right.
저는 제가 내린 모든
결정과 수사 과정 중의
I've reviewed
every decision I made.
변곡점 하나하나
되짚어보았습니다
Every inflection point
in the investigation.
그런데 어떤 합리적인 비용효과
분석에서 보더라도 내가 모든 일에서
And it is indisputable from any
rational cost benefit analysis
정확했다는 점은
반론의 여지가 없더군요
that I did everything correctly.
그러니, 왜 떨치지 못하는 겁니까?
So, why can I not move on?
왜 그 문제가
나의 가장 소중하고 유용한 이,
Why does the matter persist
in buzzing away
집중력에서 가시지 않고
at my most precious commodity,
윙윙거리고 있는 겁니까?
my concentration?
아마 모임에 가야할
운명인가보죠
Maybe we should head
for a meeting.
저는 오늘 여기
당신 피후견인이 아니라
I came here tonight,
not as your sponsee,
그들 천직이 어느 정도 흥미가
but as a friend and colleague
중첩되는 친구로서,
동료로서 왔습니다
whose vocation creates
certain overlapping interests.
이 일이 오늘 밤 제가
필요한 일이라는 점 말고도
Besides I think this is
what I need tonight.
그래요
Fine.
하지만 내일은 우리
모임에 들르는 겁니다
But tomorrow,
we're hitting a meeting.
(-)
뉴욕 최상류증의 신탁금
매니저인 도널드 하우저가
Allegations continue to mount
that Donald Hauser,
사실, 수십년간 다단계 방식
운용하고 있을 지도 모른다는
trusted money manager
to New York's elite,
혐의가 계속 쌓여가고 있습니다
may, in fact, have been running
a decades-long pyramid scheme.
증권거래위 내부 정보원이
Sources inside the SEC confirm
지금은 하우저 개인 헤지펀드를
면밀조사하고 있다고 확인해주었습니다
that they're now scrutinizing
Hauser's private hedge fund,
이 펀드는 12%이상되는 지속적인
연간 매출액을 산출한다고
which seemed to yield
consistent annual returns
여겨진 펀드입니다
of 12% or more.
제일 먼저 경보를 울린
Thanks to the work
독립언론인 로잘리 누녜즈
of independent journalist
Rosalie Nunez,
노고 덕분에
우리는 그런 매출액이
who first sounded the alarm,
모두 거짓이라는 점을
밝혀낼 지도 모릅니다
we may now discover
those returns were all lies.
그렇게 되면 하우저는
종신형으로 선고받을 수 있는
If so, Hauser will be looking
at criminal charges
형사고발을 고려해야 할 것이며
that could put him behind bars
for the rest of his life,
한편 그의 수백 명의 투자자들은
그들의 평생 예금이
while hundreds of his investors
will absorb the news
물거품처럼 사라졌다는 뉴스를
받아들여야 합니다
that their life savings
have vanished.
당사자 하우저나
회사관계자 누구도
Neither Hauser
nor anyone at his firm
논평시간에 대답하지 않았습니다
responded in time to comment.
주식은 오늘 무난히 고른
편이었습니다, 분석가들이...
Stocks were relatively flat
today, as analysts...
(-)
-
오, 맙소사!
Ow! God! Ow!
(-)
기다려
Wait.
-
.
막 자살하려던 참이었어
I was about to kill myself.
제발
Please.
한 일은 한 일이야
What's done is done.
알아. 내 말이 그 말이야
I know. That's what
I want to talk about.
여러분들 변함없이 안녕들
하시지요l...
Good morning
to you, as well...
도널드, 저에요
Donald, it's me.
♪ Elementary 2x11 ♪
Internal Audit
Original Air Date on December 12, 2013
♪ Elementary 2x11 ♪
Internal Audit
Original Air Date on December 12, 2013
밝혀내려다 누군가 화가
났던 모양이군요
Well, someone had some
anger to work out.
다른 사람 돈
Steal a few hundred
million dollars
수백만 달러를 훔쳤으니
of other people's money,
누군가 혼나야 하는 법이지
somebody's bound
to get ticked off.
누가 그를 발견했어요?
So, who found him?
개인 요리사, 들어와 보니,
Personal chef. She came in,
방범장치가 나가 있고
텔레비젼이 켜져있더래
said the alarm system was off,
and the TV was on.
여기 부엌에 있어
She's here in the kitchen.
미스, 어, 버틀러?
Miss, uh, Butler?
미스 버틀러
이쪽은 조언 왓슨입니다
Miss Butler,
this is Joan Watson.
이런 상황에서 뵙게 되어
죄송합니다
Sorry to meet
under these circumstances.
고맙습니다
Thank you.
미스 왓슨 그리고 저쪽
파트너인, 홈즈 씨
Miss Watson and her partner
there, Mr. Holmes,
경찰서 자문입니다
consult for
the department.
개인 요리사시라구요?
So, you are
a personal chef?
하우저 씨는 오랫동안
고객이셨고
Mr. Hauser was a
client for a long time.
제 집에서 그분
음식을 마련해와
I prepared meals
for him at my house
한 주에 몇 번 씩
가지고 왔습니다
and-and brought them here
a few times a week.
누구 하우저 씨 해치고자
You any idea
할만한 사람
짐작가는 데라도?
who might want
to hurt Mr. Hauser?
어, 언론에서 진행되는 걸로 봐서는
그럴 사람 많아요
Oh, with what's been going on
in the press, plenty of people.
저, 저 사람은 뭐 하는 건가요?
What-What's he doing?
(-)
저 사람, 일처리 중이에요
He, uh, has a process.
반장님?
Captain?
잠깐 실례합니다
Would you excuse me?
피해자 총이 여기서
발견되었지요?
I take it the victim's gun
was found here?
그래, 제일 처음 현장에
Yeah, by the first
온 경찰관이 발견했지
하우저에게 등록된 총이었어
uniforms on the scene.
Registered to Hauser.
하지만 마루에서 발견한
However, different caliber
탄피와 구경이 달랐어
than the casings we
found on the floor.
하우저가 자기방어를 하려던
거라 추측했지
Figured Hauser tried
to defend himself.
발사된 적은 없고
Never got a shot off.
하우저는 방어를 위해 총을
I can assure you
Mr. Hauser did not pull his gun
꺼내지 않은 건 확실합니다.
적어도-
in self-defense. At least,
처음에는 아녜요
그보다,
not at first.
Rather,
몹시 무례하게 방해받기 전에
he was about to commit suicide
막 자살하려던 참이었습니다
when he was very rudely
interrupted.
권총은 이 서랍에
보관되어 있었습니다
The handgun was stored here
in this drawer.
누가 집어들었든,
꺼내들고 나서는
Whoever removed it bothered
to close the drawer
서랍을 닫는
수고까지 했습니다
when they were done.
한창 가정침입으로 열기
충만한데 어느 쪽에서라도
This is a very unlikely action
on anyone's part
할 리가 만무한 행동이죠
during the middle
of a heated home invasion.
하우저의 총은 살인범이 들어오기
전에 나와 있었습니다
No. Mr. Hauser's gun was out
before the killer entered.
이 위스키-- 글렌 로카버
The whiskey-- Glen Lochaber,
1926년산, 단일 캐스크에
55년 숙성되어
1926, single cask,
aged for 55 years.
이제껏 오직 100병만
생산되었어요
Yum. Only 100 bottles
ever produced.
비용이 못들어도 만 달러 는
들었을 겁니다
Probably set Mr. Hauser back
about $10,000.
훌륭하기로 정평이 나 있는
물건입니다
This is the proverbial
good stuff, and,
평소 두었던 자리에 난
judging by the ring of dust
바의 둥근 먼지 흔적으로
판단을 해보면
where it usually sat
on his bar,
아주 드물디드문 경우를
위해서 이를 모셔두었습니다
he kept it for only
the very rarest of occasions.
버틀러 양이
Miss Butler
들어와 보니 텔레비젼이
said the television was on
켜져 있었다고 했습니다
when she entered.
어젯밤에 무슨 소식이 주름잡고
있었는지 다 아는 바지요
We all know what story dominated
the news last night.
하우저는 앉아서 직접 보며
Hauser himself
was sitting, watching
꼭대기까지 넘치도록
잔을 그득 채웁니다
as he filled his glass
to the very brim.
아껴봤자 이제 아무 소용 없으니까
No longer any point
in saving it.
마지막으로...
Lastly...
...입천장의 권총 기름은
...gun oil on the roof
of his mouth.
아이러니 중의 아이러니죠
The irony of ironies.
살인범은 마악 하우저가
Our killer arrived just in time
자살하기 직전 도착해
자살을 멈추었습니다
to stop Mr. Hauser
from shooting himself.
그래서, 뭐? 살인범은 처음에
고문을 해서 쥐어짜내려고 했다?
So, what? Killer just wanted to
squeeze in some torture first?
아마도 돈 돌려받는 일보다야
만족스럽진 못하겠지만,
Probably not as satisfying as
getting his or her money back,
얻어걸리는 대로 다 취하는 법
아니겠습니까
but I suppose
you take what you can get.
오. 이 기사를 보면,
Oh. According to this article,
도널드 하우저 다단계 수법에
수천 명 넘는 사람이
there could be over a thousand
people that were affected
영향을 받을 수 있다네요
by Donald Hauser's
pyramid scheme.
우리 일로 딱 적합하달만 하네요,
안 그래요?
I'd say our works cu it
for us, wouldn't you?
우리 일을 어디서 시작할지
그럴싸한 묘안이 있는 데
Actually, I've got a rather good
idea of where I'd like to start.
-그 요리사, 버틀러
-왜요?
The chef, Chloe Butler.
Why?
우리가 그 여자 면담할 때
You not see
how nervous she was
얼마나 안절부절 못하는지
못 본 모양이로군요?
when we were interviewing her?
촉각이 곤두서
무언가 숨기고 있노라,
Her haptics
were practically screaming
대놓고 소리를 지르고 있더군요
that she was hiding something.
금방 난도질 당한 시체를
Well, she just found
발견했어요
the mutilated corpse
of her boss.
알리바이 또한 뭔가 아쉬운
점이 있었죠, 아니던가?
Her alibi left something
to be desired, as well, no?
살인 시각 동안 집에
혼자 있었다는 이유만으로
Well, just because she
said she was home alone
살인을 저질렀다는
뜻은 못 되죠
during the time of the murder
doesn't mean she did it.
하지 않았다는 뜻도 아니고
Nor does it mean she didn't.
분명, 다른 용의자들도
차고도 넘치지만
Obviously, there's no shortage
of other suspects,
버틀러부터 개시해볼 만한
가치는 있는 것 같은데요
but Miss Butler seems like
a worthwhile place to start.
이야기 잠깐, 우리집, 1 시간 후?
어젯밤 벨 형사 만났죠,
안 그랬나요?
You saw Detective Bell
last night, did you not?
만났어요
Yes, I did.
그런데?
And?
좋아졌어요. 당분간은
책상만 몰고 다니고 있겠지만
He's better. He's riding
a desk for now,
적어도 자리 털고 일어나
돌아다녀요
but, um, at least
he's up and around.
사실, 벨 심부름 몇 가지
해주겠다고 약속을 했어요 .
As a matter of fact, I promised
I'd run a few errands for him.
조금 있다 돌아올 게요
-저 여기 없으면
I will be back in a bit.
If I'm not here,
사건 파일들 살펴보며
서에 있을 겁니다
I will be at the station,
reviewing case files.
당신에 문자 보내죠
혼자 쓸쓸히 하우저 씨
I will text you if I identify
Mr. Hauser's killer
살인범 알아내면요
all by my lonesome.
아침 일 죄송해요
I am sorry about this morning.
난 그저...
I... I just...
괜찮아요, 진짜
It's fine. Seriously.
아무 잘못 없어요
You didn't do anything wrong.
(-)
와, 아이도 있다니 안 믿겨져요
Oh. I can't believe
you have a baby now.
당신이 못 믿겠다고요?
You can't believe it?
-
그럼, 아이 아빠는...
So, uh, you said the dad is...
사실을 잘 모른다는 말인가요?
out of the picture?
멀쩡해졌다고 남자 고르는 재주가
I can't say
I got any better at picking men
늘었다고는 할 수 없어요
just because I got clean.
내 전....현명치 못한 결정이
갈때까지 간 건지
Ross, my ex--
as far as bad decisions go,
로스는 헤로인 방면에
따를 사람이 없었어요
he's right up there with heroin.
오.
Oh.
하지만 저는 세인을 얻었어요
But, hey, it got me Shane.
당신을 보자 내가 어째야
I had no idea
되나 아무 생각이 없었어요
what I was supposed
to do when I saw you.
당신이 직업을 바꾼 지도
몰랐고 그리고
I didn't know
you'd switched careers, and
경찰이 근처에 있다보니
정신이 없어서 당신을 안다고
with the police around,
I didn't know
해야하는 게 법적 의무가
있는 건지, 아니면...
if I was obligated by law
to say that I knew you, or...
클로에, 맞다 틀리다
할 일은 없어요
Chloe, there is no right
or wrong.
사람들 있는 데서 이전 고객을
When I run into a former
마주치게 되면
전 말을 걸지 안 걸지는
client in a social setting,
I let them decide
그 사람들 결정에 맡겨요
whether they want
to say anything or not.
당신은 허를 찔려 허둥대는
모습이라 제가 선수를 쳤어요
You were obviously caught
off guard, so I took the lead.
내 삶의 그 부분만은 누구에게도
I just try not to tell anyone
말하지 않으려고요
about that part of my life.
저기, 만약 그럴 수만 있다면요
You know, if-if I can help it.
여전히 모임에 가나요?
Are you still
going to meetings?
예, 물론이죠
Oh, yeah, of course.
아, 아니, 아무에게도
말 안한다는 뜻은 아니었어요
No, I-I don't mean
I don't talk to anyone,
전...
I just...
그 "익명 모임"만은 진지하게
참여해요
take the "anonymous"
part seriously.
실은 그게 제가 당신을 만나기를
Actually, that's
one of the reasons
원했던 이유 중에 하나에요
I wanted
to see you.
당신이 허락하면
나는 우리 과거를
With your permission,
I would like to explain
제 파트너에게 설명했으면 해요
our history
to my partner.
왜요? // 그는 대단히 통찰력이
뛰어난 사람이에요
Why?
He's very perceptive.
당신이 어젯밤에 무언가 숨긴다고
감도 잡았는데
He could tell that you were
hiding something last night.
도널드 하우저에게 일어난 일과
He thought it might
have something to do
관련있을 지도 모른다고 생각해요
with what happened
to Donald Hauser.
그 사람은 제가 용의자로
생각하나요?
He thinks I'm a suspect?
당신은 그저 그 사람
눈길을 끄는 사람이에요
You're just someone
who caught his eye.
마음이 영 불편하면
Look, if you don't
feel comfortable,
조르지는 않을 게요
I totally
understand.
괜찮다면...
If you do...
우리의 기밀유지 동의가
know that our
confidentiality
홈즈 또한 해당된다고
점을 알아두세요
agreement will
extend to him as well.
저는 그저 우리 수사가
올바른 방향으로 나가기를
I just want to make
sure the investigation
바라는 마음에서 하는 부탁이에요
is moving in the
right direction.
정말 그 사람을 믿는군요
You must really trust him.
믿어요
I do.
헤이.
Hey.
클로에 버틀러 이야기 좀 할까요?
Can we talk about
Chloe Butler?
2009에 그녀는 뉴욕에서 가장
잘 나가는 주방장 중 한 명이었어요
In 2009, she was one of the
hottest chefs in the city.
그래요, 조사하다가
그건 봤어요
Yes, I saw that
when I looked into her.
그 이면 전부는 못 봤어요
Well, you didn't see all of it.
관심이 너무 부담스러운데다
The attention was
too much for her,
잘못된 사람들과 어울려 다녔어요
and she fell in
with the wrong crowd.
언제 당신과 일을 시작했나요?
When did she start
working with you?
2011.
첫 고객 중 한 명이에요
She was one of my first clients.
육 개월 조금 넘게
그녀와 살았어요
I lived with her for
a little over six months.
쉽지는 않았지만 그녀 삶은
원래 궤도로 돌아왔죠
It wasn't easy, but she got
her life back on track.
식당분야는 도화선이
될 수 있다고 깨닫고
She knew that the restaurant
scene could be a trigger,
새로운 사업을 시작했어요
so she started a new business.
개인 요리사로
As a personal chef.
그래요. 그러니 당신이 지난 밤
Yes. So everything you sensed
그녀가 숨기고 있다고 감지한 일은
that she was hiding last night
그녀의 과거에 관한 거예요
was about
her past.
그리고 그녀는 살인사건 시각에
And she has an alibi
알리바이가 있어요
for the time of the murder.
자신의 후견인과 있었어요
She was with her sponsor.
흠
Hmm.
허, 다른 중독자를
만났는데 제가 탐지하지
Well, it's interesting
that I failed to detect
못했다는 게 흥미롭군요
another addict when I met one.
당신이 내게 무언가 숨기는 줄
꿈에도 몰랐다는 게
More interesting that
I didn't get a sense
더더욱 흥미롭지만, 어쨌든...
that you were hiding something
from me, but anyway...
그런 경우라면
In that case,
우리는 도널드 하우저 살인에서
다른 잠재적인 용의자 명단을
we should, uh, focus on
culling our list
골라 모으는 일에
집중해야겠습니다
of other potential suspects
in Donald Hauser's murder.
다단계 방식 특종을
처음 터뜨린 언론인
I left a voicemail
with the journalist
음성사서함에 메시지를 남겼어요
who broke the story
of his pyramid scheme,
이름이 로잘리 누네즈였던가
a woman named Rosalie Nunez.
운이 따르면, 무언가 견식이
있으면 우리는 하우저의 희생자
Any luck, she will have some
insight which we can use
조사에 우선순위 매기는데
이용해 볼 수도 있으니.
to prioritize our investigation
of Hauser's victims.
실은 클로에가 이미 그런 면으로
도움이 될 지도 몰라요
Actually, Chloe may have
already helped with that.
생각지도 못하고 있었는데
이야기를 나누다 보니
She didn't think of it
until we were talking,
마지막으로 살아 있는 하우저를
but she had
an idea who
봤을 지도 모를
사람이 떠올랐다는군요
the last person might've been
to see Hauser alive.
어, 제이콥 와이스라고
비영리 단체 책임자에요
Uh, the director of a nonprofit
named Jacob Weiss.
하우저는 어젯밤에
추가분을 준비하라고 시켰는데
Hauser had her prepare an
extra meal for last night.
일의 일부가 어떤 친구가
무엇을 먹는지 아는 일이래요
Part of her job is to know
which friends ate what.
그 소식 정말 충격이었습니다
I was shocked
when I heard the news.
여직, 믿기지가 않아요
I-I still don't
believe it.
제가 간 후 한참 후에
벌어진 일은 아닐 텐데
It couldn't have happened
that many hours after I left.
저희 소견도 똑 같습니다
Our thoughts
exactly.
사실, 그날 저녁 나머지 시간의
소재를 해명하실 수 있는지
In fact, we're curious
if you could account
여쭙고 싶습니다
for your whereabouts for
the rest of the evening.
검시의는 하우저 씨 죽음을
10 pm에서 자정 사이 일어난
The M.E. puts Mr. Hauser's
death somewhere between
일이라고 잡더군요
10:00 p.m. and midnight.
도널드 집을 떠난 이후에
펄레디언 호텔에서
After I left Donald,
I had a late meeting
늦은 시간 스위스 은행가
at the Palladian Hotel
조나스 비츠와 만남을 가졌습니다
with a Swiss banker
named Jonas Bitz.
상당히 늦게까지 있어서
그나 로비 바에 있던 아무나
We were there quite late.
I'm sure he or anyone
그 점은 입증해 줄 거예요
at the lobby bar
will confirm that.
하지만...전 도널드를 죽여야 할
어떤 이유도 없는 사람이에요
But... I'm the last person
who had a reason to kill Donald.
우리가 아는 바로는 하우저 씨가
자선 단체 재정을...
Well, it's our understanding
that he handled your...
다룬 걸로 아는데요
charity's finances.
일어난 일을 모든 일을 고려하면,
Considering everything
that's happened,
그 정도면 동기가 되죠
that would
give you motive.
실은 그럴 리가 없어요.
Actually, it wouldn't.
우리가 무슨 일 하는지 아십니까?
Do you know what we do here?
홀로코스트 생존자 배상을
추구하고 있죠
You seek reparations
for survivors of the Holocaust.
오늘날까지 나찌 전쟁모리배에게
속한 스위스 은행계좌가
To this day, Swiss bank accounts
are still being identified
여전히 확인되고 있어요
that belong
to Nazi war profiteers.
우리 조사관들은 그런
돈을 발굴하고
Our investigators
uncover that money
생존자나 그들 가족을 대변해
청구 신청을 진행해요
and process claims on behalf
of survivors and their families.
언론에서 도널드에 관해
들은 말을 부인은 할 수 없지만
I can't deny what I'm hearing
in the press about Donald,
그는 제 친구에요
그는 아무 수임없이
but he was my friend.
He donated his services
이 기관의 공인회계사로서
편익을 기부했어요
free of charge,
as this council's CPA.
우리의 투자에 관해서도
And as for our investments,
기관에서는 한푼도 잃은
적이 없어요
the council never
lost a dime.
동전 하나까지 이미
내역이 보고되었죠
Every penny has already
been accounted for.
왜 그가 이 기관만 건드리지 않고
두었는지 짐작가는 데라도 있습니까?
Can you think of why he might've
left the council alone?
아마 다른 사람들 돈을
훔치고 있었으니,
Maybe as he was
stealing from others,
우리를 위한 일을 마치 일종의...
he saw his work for us
as a kind of...
업보의 평형추라고 보지
않았을까요? 나쁜 일에 대해
karmic counterbalance, a way
to do some good to make up
좋은 일로 벌충하려는.
for the bad.
이유가 무엇이건,
저야 고맙죠
Whatever the reason,
I'm grateful.
그럼, 도널드 하우저는
마음씨 곱고 순수한
So, Donald Hauser
was a swindler
협잡꾼이로군요
with a heart of gold.
아주 드물게만 사람들은
완전히 선하거나
Very few of us are
either completely good
완전히 악해요.
하우저라도 결코 넘지 않을
or completely evil.
It would appear
도덕의 선을 지니고 있었나 보죠
that even Hauser had a moral
line that he would not cross.
(-)
좋았어. 로잘리 누녜즈에요
제가 말했던 그 리포터
Excellent. This is Rosalie
Nunez, the reporter I mentioned.
누녜즈 양, 답변전화 주셔서
정말 감사드립니다
Ms. Nunez, thank you so much
for calling me back.
셜록 홈즈 씨인가요?
Is this Sherlock Holmes?
맞습니다만, 누구신지?
It is. Who's this?
NYPD 형사 런츠입니다
This is Detective Luntz
of the NYPD.
음성사서함에
당신이.. 자문역이라고
You left a voice mail
for Ms. Nunez
메시지를 남기셨더군요?
saying you were a... consultant?
그런 말 했고 자문 맞습니다
I did and I am.
왜 그분 전화를 가지고 계세요?
Why do you have her phone?
그분 거주지로 오셔야
될 듯 합니다
I think maybe you should join me
at her residence
그래서 직접 설명을 하게요
so I can explain in person.
저도 몇 가지 당신에게 자문할 게
있을 수도 있고요
I may even have some
consulting questions for you.
누녜즈도 도널드 하우저를
살해한 동일 인물이
Well, it looks like Ms. Nunez
was killed by the same person
죽인 것처럼 보이네요
who murdered Donald Hauser.
묶는데 사용한 기술이며,
The technique used
to bind her, the size
총상의 크기며 위치며
and placement
of the bullet wounds.
탄도시험 결과가 이를 확인해
주리라 적지않은 확신이 드네요
I'm quite confident a ballistics
report will confirm that.
우리 사수께서는 이틀전
꽤나 바쁘게 밤을 지냈군
Our shooter had a busy
night two nights ago.
검시의가 사망 추정 시간이
M.E. put tentative
time of death
하우저 사망보다 불과 한두 시간
뒤라는군
only a few hours after Hauser's.
런츠에게 서둘러 탄도 검사
하라고 이르지
I'm gonna tell Luntz to put
a rush on ballistics.
이건 말이 안 돼요
This doesn't
make any sense.
왜 똑 같은 사람이
사람들이 평생 모은 돈을
Why would the same person
want to kill both the man
훔친 사람과 이를 밝혀낸
리포터 둘 다
who stole people's
life's savings
죽이기를 원하겠느냐고요?
and the reporter
who exposed him?
이쪽이 미우면 저쪽은 광적으로
Seems like if you hated one,
좋아하기 마련이잖아요
you'd be a fan of the other.
드물긴 해도 문학적인 경우
사람들이 그 전달자를
Rare to come across
such a literal case
죽이는 사례를 마주치기도 해요
of someone shooting
the messenger.
여기 다 노트북 전원을
꽂았던 거 같은네
Looks like she plugged in
her laptop here.
노트북이 없어졌는지
알아봐야겠어요
We should find out
if it's missing.
와서 이것 좀 보세요
Come and have a look at this.
살인자는 무력으로 침입했어요
The killer entered by force.
여기 문을 찼어요
Kicked the door here.
음. 오사쥬 오렌지 과즙이군요
잘못 안 게 아니라면
Mmm. Sap of the Osage orange,
unless I'm mistaken.
전 됐어요
I'm good.
조금 부적절한 명칭이에요. 진짜
Bit of a misnomer, really.
희미한 감귤 향을 제외하면
- Aside from a vague...
- citrusy scent,
오렌지와는 무관하죠
it is unrelated
to the orange.
실제로는 계통이 오디와 더
가까운 친척이죠
It's a closer cousin
to the mulberry, actually.
살인자가 문을 찼는데
So, killer kicked in the door,
그 발에 있던 과즙이 이사갔군요
transferred the sap
from his shoe.
그런고로 여기로 오는 길로 택한
가장 가능성 있는 경로를 알려주지요
Which tells us the most likely
route he took on his way here.
"멍키 볼즈"
"Monkey balls."
뭐라셨어요?
Beg your pardon?
오사쥬 오렌지를 이르는
많은 전통 이름 중 하나에요
One of the many folk names
for the Osage orange.
다람쥐가 과일 여기저기를 찢고
Squirrels rip the fruit apart,
씨와 과즙을 땅위에 흩뿌려요
spreading the seeds and the sap
on the ground.
이 공원은 누녜즈 아파트
반경 내에서
This park is the only place
in the vicinity
이를 찾을 가능성이 있는
of Ms. Nunez's apartment
where one is likely
유일한 곳이에요
to find one of these.
그녀를 쏜 사람은
여기를 걸어 지나
So you think whoever shot her
walked through here
아파트로 갔다고 생각하는군요
on his way to her apartment.
아마도 떠날 때도
And perhaps again when he left.
(-)
그거 알프레도 링톤 아녜요?
Isn't that Alfredo's ringtone?
그래요, 나를 계속 괴롭히네요
어제 그하고 모임에
Yes, he's been harassing me.
I promised
가겠다고 약속을 해서
I would go to a meeting
with him yesterday,
하지만 수사가 우선권을 얻었고
but the investigation
took precedence.
그리고 여전히 우선이고.
It still does.
(-)
이거 잘 봐!
Check it out,
check it out!
보시게나, 왓슨,
Behold, Watson,
한 세대가 나르시시즘에
넋이 나간 모습이로고
a generation lost
to narcissism.
어떤 경험도
업로드해서 온당한 몫의
A populace who believes
that no experience is
히트 수를 기록하지 않으면
worth having
unless it's been uploaded
가치가 없다고 여기는
대중들이에요
and received
its fair share of hits,
그런 업적의 정점은
철제 난간에
for whom the pinnacle of
achievement is having the moment
자신의 음부를 짓찧은 순간을
가지는 이들은 "밈(meme)"의
you crush your genitalia
on a metal railing
자격을 성취하지요
(meme: 비유전적 문화요소)
achieve "meme" status.
그래도 자기 도취적인 그들이
이 순간에는 도움이 되네요
And yet their self-absorption
may, in this instance, serve us.
경찰 라디오 수신으로 어쩌다
알게되었는데 경찰들은
I happen to know from my
police scanner that the police
스케이트보더 쫓느라
이 공원에 자주 불려와요
are often called to this park
to chase skateboarders away.
이들은, 공원 드나드는 사람들
낭패스럽게, 종일 죽치고 있죠
They are, to the dismay of some
parkgoers, here at all hours.
그러니 살인자가 걸어가던 때
이틀 전에도 있었다면
So if they were here two nights
ago when the killer walked by,
저들 중 누군가 핸드폰에
잡혔을 수도 있군요
one of them might have caught
them on their cell phone.
제가 나르시스트들과
이야기 나눠보죠
I will talk to the narcissists.
알프레도 만나러 가고
모임에 가도 되어요
You go meet Alfredo
so you can get to a meeting.
응급실 돌때 이런 얘들
수없이 꿔매 봤으니
I've stitched up
a lot of these guys
그들에게 어떻게 말 붙이나
잘 알아요
back during my E.R. rotation.
I know how to talk to them.
백치 말을 해요?
You speak idiot?
또한 당신 기분 째질듯
좋아보이지도 않는군요
You also don't seem like
you're in the greatest mood.
이 일은 보다 더 부드러운
접근이 필요할 지도 몰라요
This might need a softer touch.
뭔가 드러나면
I'll let you know
알려드릴 게요
if anything turns up.
알프레도 아니네요
You're not Alfredo.
당신이 셜록이죠, 맞죠?
You're Sherlock, right?
그러시는 댁은?
And you are?
랜디 (randy)
Randy.
-이름인가요, 형용사인가요?
-예에?
Name or adjective?
What?
"랜덜"의 줄임말인지?
아님, 성적으로 흥분한 상태인지?
Short for "Randall"?
Or state of sexual arousal?
당신 내가 섰나 묻는 거요?
Are you asking me if I'm horny?
이같은 차는 어떤 이들에게
그런 효과를 내기도 하죠
Well, cars like this can have
that effect on some men.
셜록?
Sherlock?
둘이 안면 텄군요
I see you
guys have met.
아, 잠시동안 당신 집에
잠입자가 있는 줄 알았어요
Ah. I thought for a moment that
your home had been infiltrated.
그런 경우가 아닌게로군요
I see that's not the case.
랜디하고 나는 몇 달 전에
모임에서 만났어요
No, Randy and I met at a
meeting a few weeks ago.
끊은 지 석달입니다
Three months sober.
이제껏 혼자서 하고 있었는데...
He's been going it
alone for now, but...
며칠전 밤 이야기를 나눠보고 ...
we were talking a few
nights ago, and...
후견인을 두어도 괜찮겠다고
생각했지요
we think he might
benefit from a sponsor.
옙, 현명한 결정에
Yep. Yep. A wise decision.
예. 그리고... 선택도 훌륭하고
Yeah. And a... excellent choice.
그래요, 어,
알프레도는, 어
Yeah, um,
Alfredo has, uh,
지난 18개월 동안 충심으로
나를 도와주었어요, 그러니, 어
helped me profoundly
over the last 18 months, so, uh,
당신은 탁월한 수완가를
만난 겁니다
yeah, you're in excellent hands.
실은 말예요
Actually, I
was thinking
그 일 맡을 사람으로
당신을 점찍어 두었어요
that you might be
the man for the job.
알프레도가 당신에게
Alfredo tells me
많이 배울 거라고 하더군요
I can learn a lot from you.
예에...
Yeah. Um...
잠깐 실례해도 괜찮을는지요?
could you just...
Could you give us a moment?
아주 잠시면 되는데
We'll just be one
second, all right?
농담 마세요
You're joking.
당신이 후견인 되는 일이
Do you think the idea of you
웃기지도 않은 일이라고 생각해요?
내 생각은 다른데
becoming a sponsor is funny?
Because I don't.
한참 동안 머리 굴려서 나온
생각이에요, 아시겠죠?
I've been thinking about
it for a while, okay?
지난밤 털어놓던 고민 듣고
생각이 옳다구나 굳혔죠
The stuff you said the other
night pretty much sealed it.
무슨 "고민"요?
What "stuff"?
지난 몇 주 동안 안절부절
Do you want to know
why you've been
왜 그렇게 속을 태웠나
알고 싶어요?
so agitated
for the last few weeks?
왜 그렇게 자꾸 다른데
정신이 팔릴까요?
Why you've been
so distracted?
당신 친구에게 생긴 일에
속이 안좋기 때문이에요
Because you feel bad about
what happened to your friend.
말씀드렸잖아요
I told you.
전적으로 저는 도리에 맞았어요
I was completely in the right.
아마 예전 당신이라면
그걸로도 충분했겠지만
Maybe for the old you,
that would've been enough.
지금은 아녜요
But not now.
지금은 다른 사람이에요
You're different now.
당신은 프로그램에 참여를 했고
You committed yourself
to the program
다른 사람들 하는 이야기에
귀도 기울였어요
and now you heard other people
tell their stories.
약간의 공감이 스며들었죠
And a little empathy crept in.
그건 벌어질 일이 벌어진 것이고
That's what's
supposed to happen.
그렇게 일이 돌아가고 있어요
That's how it works.
당신은 벨 형사를 돕고 싶지만
그가 못하게 해요
You want to help Detective
Bell, but he won't let you.
돕고자 하는 본능은
갖고 있으면 좋은 감정이에요
That is a good instinct to have.
어디 다른 곳에
Why not try to apply it
적용하는 일도 나쁠 건 없죠
somewhere else?
후견인이 되는 일은
여유가 있어야 됩니다
Being a sponsor
means being available.
당신은 저도 알고,
제 일도 잘 알잖아요
You know me. You know my work.
온통 다 쏟아붓는 일이에요
It's all-consuming.
모임 시간은 용케 마련하잖아요?
You find time for meetings,
don't you?
-
오
Oh.
죄송한데. 어쨌든 오늘 모임은
I'm sorry. I won't be able
도저히 참석 못하겠군요
to make this evening's meeting
after all.
일이 생겨서
Duty calls.
늘 그럴 테지만
As it always will.
(-)
뭐 건진 거라도?
스위치와 페이키(뒤로가기) 사이
Any luck?
Aside from getting a master class
차이점을 두고 상급교육을
받은 일 말고는, 없어요
in the difference between
a switch and a fakie, no.
지나는 사람 아무도
의심스럽다 눈에 확 틔지 않아요
No one walking by
jumped out as suspicious.
모임은 어땠어요?
How was the meeting?
어쩌면 꽤 좋았을 수도
나야 알 도리가 없지만
Probably quite good.
I will never know.
알프레도 집에 도착하자마자
Because as soon as
I got to Alfredo's,
제가 매복공격의 피해자가
되는 바람에
I was the victim
of an ambush.
무슨 소리하는 거예요?
What are you talking about?
제가 후견인 역할을 할 때라는
의견을 피력하더군요
He expressed his opinion that
it was time I became a sponsor.
오~
Oh.
뭐라 답했어요?
And what did you say?
내 삶은 누군가 다른 사람이
위기에 처할 때마다 짬을 내어
I told him my life is not
conducive to making myself
뒷바라지할 처지가
못 된다고 말했죠
available every time
someone else was in crisis.
다들 그렇지, 안 그런
사람 있기는 한가요?
You do get
that no one's life is, right?
오, 이런이런
Oh, my God.
뭔데요?
What is it?
저 가방 든 남자
The man with the bag.
아는 사람이에요
I know him.
세상 좁네요
Small world.
그렇게 좁지는 않아요
Not that small.
이름이 기억 안 나요
I don't remember his name.
처음 클로에하고 일하기 시작할 때
몇 번 마주친 적 있어요
We crossed paths when I first
started working with Chloe.
언젠가 밤에 아파트에
온 적 있고
He came to her apartment one night.
Are you saying
도널드 하우저의 시체를 발견한
클로에 버틀러와
there's a connection between
Chloe Butler, who discovered
로절리 누녜즈가
죽은지 얼마 안 되어
Donald Hauser's body,
and a man seen
근처에 있던 남자간에
무언가 연결점이 있다
in the vicinity
of Rosalie Nunez's apartment
그말 인가요?
shortly after her murder?
당신 말이 맞아요--
세상은 좁지 않아요
You're right--
the world is not that small.
믿을 수가 없네
하지만, 넬슨이에요
I can't believe it,
but yeah, that's Nelson.
넬슨 매덕스
죽은 리포터 아파트
Nelson Maddox.
You said this was taken
바깥에서 찍힌 사진이라고요?
outside the apartment
of the reporter who died?
몇 블럭 떨어져서
A few blocks away.
내가 어떻게 이 사람
You know how
알아봤는지 알죠?
I recognized him, right?
그날밤 여기 계셨죠
You were here that night.
그 사람 들이닥치던 날
The night he came over.
당신에게 고함을 치기에
그냥, 당신 전남친
He was yelling at you.
I mean, I assumed
이려니 추측했는데 하지만...
he was your ex, but...
그 일에 관해 이야기하고 싶어
하지 않아, 나도 캐묻지 않았죠
you didn't want to talk
about it, so I didn't push.
넬슨하고 저하고..
Nelson and I were...
어울려 다니던...
together...
제가 약을 사용할 적에요
도널드는 아직 식당에
when I was using.
Donald used to bring him
일할 적에 그 사람을 곧잘
식당으로 데려왔어요
into the restaurant
when I still worked there.
그가 우리를 소개시켜줬죠
He introduced us.
넬슨은 그가 중개인이라고 했어요
Uh, Nelson said
he was an entrepreneur.
하지만 '범죄'를 그런 식으로
일컫는다는 걸 알게되었죠
But then I realized that was
his way of saying "criminal."
무슨 종류의 범죄요?
What kind of criminal?
저도 몰라요
무언가 약과 관련된 일
I don't know.
Something with drugs.
그 사람 항상 약을 지니고 있었고
He always had a fix,
그 당시에는
제게는 그게 전부였죠
and back then,
that's all that mattered to me.
하지만 재활원 나온 뒤...
But after rehab...
다시 그를 만날 수 없다고
이야기를 했고...
I told him that
I couldn't see him again, and...
화를 내었죠 그리고...
he got angry, and...
나를 보러 와서...
he came to see me...
괜찮아요. 쉬엄쉬엄 해요
It's okay, take your time.
다시는 그를 보지 못했어요
I never saw
him again,
이 사진 보여주기 전까지는요
not till you showed me his picture.
How did he
그 사람하고 도널드는
어떻게 아는 사이에요?
and Donald
know each other?
넬슨이 사업상 고객이었나요?
Was Nelson
a business client?
예. 예,
거의 그랬을 거예요
Yeah. Yeah,
I'm pretty sure he was.
도널드가 그사람에게 사기쳤다면
Well, if Donald swindled him,
그를 죽일 만한 동기가 돼요
then he would have motive
to kill him.
하지만 왜 로잘리를 해쳤을까 ?
But why hurt Rosalie?
조언...
Joan...
당신 절대 이 일
입밖에 내서는 안 돼요
you know you can't
tell anyone about this.
넬슨이 알아 본 유일한 이유가
The only reason that
you recognized Nelson
교정동반자로 여기 있었기
때문이에요
was because you were here
as my sober companion.
경찰에게 어떻게 알게
되었는지 설명하려면
If you tell the police
how you knew him,
당신은 저에 관해, 과거에
대해 말해야만 할 거예요
you're gonna have to tell them
about me, about my past.
클로에 말 나오는 거 꺼리는
건 알지만 ...
Chloe... I know you don't like
to talk about it, but...
이해 못하세요
You don't understand.
저는 세인의 양육권을 두고
다투고 있어요
I am in a custody battle
for Shane.
애 아빠는 이전 삶은
알지 못해요
His father doesn't know anything
about my life before.
무-무슨 소리에요?
Wh-What do you mean?
변호사들은 몰라요
The lawyers
don't know.
법원도 몰라요
The court doesn't know.
내가 중독자라는 사실이
지금에사 밝혀지면
If it comes out now
that I'm an addict,
제가 일부러 숨긴 것처럼
되어요--
I mean, i-it looks
like I hid it--
이를 세인을 데려갈
빌미로 삼을 수도 있고
they could use it
to take Shane away.
두 사람이 죽었어요
Two people are dead.
그럼 저도 끝장이에요
And that kills me, Joan.
당신은 기밀유지협정에
서명했어요
But you signed a
confidentiality agreement.
나를 보호하겠다 약속도 했고요
You gave your word
that you would protect me.
미안하지만...
I am sorry...
넬슨과 도널드 사이를
관련짓고 싶다면
but if you want
to connect Nelson to Donald,
다른 방도를 찾아야 할 거예요
you're gonna have
to find another way.
내가 잘 이해했나
따져봅시다--
Let's make sure
I understand you--
우리가 도널드 하우저와
we now have a name
로잘리 누녜즈를 잔혹하게
살해했다고 믿을 만한
to put to the face of the man
that we believe
남자의 얼굴에 이름까지
알게 되었는데
brutally murdered
Donald Hauser and Rosalie Nunez,
수사당국과는 이런 정보를 나눌
수는 없다?
but we can't share it
with the authorities?
클로에를 배제하고 그 두 점을
연결할 수 없다면 못 해요
Not unless we can connect the dots
without involving Chloe.
이 경우에는 어느 쪽이건
똑같은 일이다, 왜냐
Which, in this case,
is the same thing,
클로에가 연결점이라서
because Chloe is the connection.
그리고 이 모든 게
당신이 다른 직업일 때
And all this
over a promise
맺은 약속 덕분에?
you made in another career?
그래요, 우리가 처음 일을
시작할 때 당신에게
Yes. Just like the
promise I made you
약속했던 일과 똑같죠 뭐
when we first started
working together.
그 당시 사람들에게 나를
뭐라고 했더라?
Uh, what was it you told
people I was back then?
아 맞다, 개인 시종이었지
Ah. A personal valet.
우리의 기밀협정이 혹여
If our confidentiality
agreement had ever come
우리와 살인자 사이에
끼어든다면
between us and a murderer,
생각이고자시고 없이 내가
중독자노라 밝힐 텐데요
I would have exposed myself
as an addict in a heartbeat.
이건 클로에가 남부끄러운
사람이라거나 그런 게 아녜요
This is not about
Chloe being ashamed.
그 보다 일이 더 커요--
아이를 잃을 수도 있다고요
It's bigger than that--
she could lose her child.
아이 아버지가 발견할지언정
그럴 가능성은 떨어지고
That's unlikely even if
the boy's father did find out,
분명 그러리는 확실성과도
한참이나 멀어요
and it's far from a certainty
that he will.
도널드 하우저는
형편없는 인간이었어요
Donald Hauser
was an execrable human being.
로잘리 누녜즈는 아니에요
Rosalie Nunez was not.
가족도 있고
가족은 그녀를 사랑했어요
She had a family;
they loved her.
친구도 동료도 있고--
많은 사람들이 하우저 일을 밝혀
She had friends, colleagues--
many people consider her a hero
영웅이라고 여겨요...
이건 토론거리가 못 되어요
for exposing Hauser...
This is not up for discussion.
우리는 매덕스와 하우저를 연결할
다른 길을 찾아야해요
We have to find another way
to connect Maddox to Hauser.
우리가 이 다른 연결점을
찾아 헤매는 동안,
And while we look
for this other connection,
매덕스는 여전히 활개를 치고
다니며 자유로이
Mr. Maddox remains at large,
뒷수습 벌이거나 사라지겠죠
적어도 반장에게 우리가 밝혀 낸
free to cover his tracks or disappear.
We should at least
일을 말해 주어야해요
상황을 설명해요, 하지만
tell the captain what we've uncovered.
Explain the situation,
클로에의 신분은 여전히 비밀로
남으리라 보장한다고도 하고
but make it clear that Chloe's
identity is to remain a secret.
저 그런 제안했어요, 됐어요?
안 된다고 말했고
I suggested that,
okay? She said no.
어찌 되었건 밀고 나간다면?
그 여자 알게 뭐에요?
What if we do it anyway?
Why must she ever know?
당신 해결방안은 나를
거짓말장이로 만드는 셈이에요
So your solution is
to make a liar out of me,
기껏 당신은 믿을 수 있다
말해두었는데?
after I told her
that she could trust you?
바로 그 해결방안 문턱까지
데려갔잖아요, 왓슨!
I have us at the very doorstep
of a solution, Watson!
벨한테 일어난 일에서
배운 게 하나도 없어요?
Did you not learn anything
from what happened to Bell?
그 사람은 우리가 한 선택으로
다쳤다고요!
He got hurt because of
choices that we made!
그가 위험에 놓일 거라고
내다볼 수 있을 방법은 없었어요
There was no way to predict that
he would be placed in danger.
마찬가지로 클로에 이름을
수사에 끌어들인다면
Just like there's no way to know
what's gonna happen to Chloe
클로에에게 일어날 일을 우리가
알 수 있는 방법도 없어요
if we drag her name
into this investigation.
-
경보장치 해치웠네요
You beat the alarm.
오직 시간문제였죠
Only a matter of time.
그리고 우리집 경보도
And my home alarm.
애들 장난 갖고
Child's play.
당신 전문직이 무색할 정도로
격이 떨어지더군요
Not really befitting
a man in your line of work.
이것들은 대체해야 할 겁니다
You might want to replace these.
(-)
.
딱 봐도 할 말 많아보이는데
자, 말해 봐요
Well, obviously you want
to talk, so talk.
저는 제가 조사하는 범죄
I've always had compassion
희생자들에게 항상
연민을 느꼈어요
for the victims of the
crimes I investigate.
다른 사람의 입장에 서 보는
제 능력은, 그러니까,
My capacity to place myself
in other people's shoes,
무슨 생각 하는지, 느끼는지
상상하는 일은...
to imagine what they're
thinking and feeling, is a...
동기를 결정하는데
필수적인 기술이에요
is a necessary skill
in determining motive.
남들보다 탁월한 기술 중 하나죠
One at which I excel.
이런 능력이...
This capacity...
제 일을 훼방놓은
적은 한 번도 없었어요
has never been a
detriment to my work.
최근에는, 하지만...
Lately, however...
벨이 늘 마음에
떠오른다, 그런 뜻이로군요
Bell's been on your
mind; I get it.
그리고 당신은 내게 피후견인을
떠맡겨서 이런 문제를
And you would risk
exacerbating this problem
점층시키는 위험을
무릅 쓰려고 하고
by assigning me a sponsee.
아무도 당신에게 아무 일
"떠맡기는" 것 아녜요
No one's
"assigning" you anything.
그런 식으로 일이
돌아가지 않아요
That's not how it works.
난 그냥 당신이 준비되었다고
생각해요
I just think you're ready.
당신 생각에 이 일에...
You think it's gonna...
초점 맞추다보면,
형사의 상황에 관련되어
focus me,
and provide a relief valve
내가 겪고 있는 모든
감정들의 배출구를
for all the feelings
I've been having
제공할 거다 이런...
regarding
the detective's situation.
설사 내가 그럴 작정이었대도
한 가지는 명심해야 해요
Even if I did, there's
one thing you got to remember.
이 일은 당신에 관한 일이 아녜요
It's not about you.
(-)
당신은 이 과정에서
많은 것을 얻었어요
You've gotten a lot
out of the program.
좀 갚을 때도 되었다
생각 안 들어요?
Don't you think it's time
to give something back?
-
일찍이도 시작했네요
Early start, I see.
밤이 늦었죠, 사실,
잠을 자렸는데 잠이 안 와서
Late night, actually.
I tried to sleep but couldn't,
그래서 그냥 붙잡고 앉았어요
so I stayed at it.
클로에가 매덕스가 하우저
고객이라고 했는데
Chloe said Maddox was
a client of Hauser's,
이름이 하우저 계좌
어디에도 없어요
but his name is not in any
of Hauser's accounts.
열두번도 더 기록을
뒤져보았는데--
I've been over the
records a dozen times--
두 사람 사이 고리를
발견할 수가 없어요
I cannot find a link
between the two.
우리가 혹시 메덕스가
하우저 다단계 계략으로
If we were able to establish
that Maddox lost money
돈을 잃은 일을 증명하다면
클로에는 벙긋하지도 않고
on Hauser's pyramid scheme,
we would have our connection
연고를 연결지었겠죠...
without implicating Chloe...
매덕스의 살인 동기 또한
연결짓고.
as well as Maddox's
motive for murder.
그러는 동안에
그렉슨 반장에게 공원에 있던
In the meantime,
I sent Captain Gregson
매덕스의 사진을 보냈어요
the video of Maddox in the park
언론에 이를 배포하라고
납득시켰어요
and convinced him
to release it to the press.
당신 말이 맞았어요
You were right.
그를 끌고 들어오면
적어도 우리는 시간을 벌게 되고
it'll at least buy us some time.
If we bring him in,
취조실에서 마주앉아 털다보면
다른 연결점도 얻어걸릴 수 있죠
And getting him in a room might
shake out another connection.
-클로에에 대해 반장에게 말했어요?
-아니요, 로잘리 아파트에
Did you tell the captain about Chloe?
No. Remember how
노트북이 없다고
했던 말 기억나죠?
I noticed Rosalie's laptop
was missing from her apartment?
그걸 파고들었는데--
찾은 적이 없더라고요
Well, I looked into it--
it never turned up.
그래서 반장님께 로잘리
문의 과즙을 봤다는 이야기,
Then I told the captain
about the sap on Rosalie's door
그렇게 공원에 도달했다고
이야기했고
and how that led us to the park.
그러고는 살인사건이
Then I sent him the video
있던 시각 즈음에 매독스가
어깨에 노트북을 매고
of Maddox walking away
with a laptop bag
공원을 지나고 있는 비디오를
보냈어요
slung over his shoulder right
around the time of the murder.
매덕스 이름은 댈 수 없었어요
I couldn't give him
Maddox's name
클로에 이름을 올리지 않는한에는
without bringing up, Chloe,
of course,
하지만 적어도 그 사람 얼굴은
밖에 내걸렸어요
but at least his
face is out there.
이게 이상적이 아니란 건 알지만
I know it's not ideal.
하지만 상황을 놓고 보면
But given the circumstances,
거의 말 그대로 우리가 할 수
있는 최선이랄 수 있죠
it was quite literally
all that we could do.
잘했어요
Well done.
-
그렉슨 반장이에요
It's Captain Gregson.
누군가 매덕스 얼굴을
뉴스에서 보고서
Someone saw Maddox's
face on the news
정보를 제공했다네요
and called in a tip.
봉사활동하는 회원 한 명이
A member of your outreach staff
귀 단체에서 한 일년 전에 열었던
met him at
a fund-raiser
기금마련 자리에서 만났답니다
your organization threw
about a year ago.
그분이 우리를 위해
손님 명단을 찾아봐 주셨고
She dug up
the guest list for us.
명단에 이름이 올랐더군요
The list gave
us a name:
넬슨 매덕스
Nelson Maddox.
이 사람 기억납니다
I remember him.
도널드를 통해 만났죠
I met him through Donald.
도널드가 기금 마련자리에
I-I think Donald
was the one
그를 초대했던 걸로 기억하는데
who invited him
to the fund-raiser.
두 사람 관계에 먼눈치라도
Do you think
you'd be able to shed
혹 아실 만한 게있을는지요?
any light
on their relationship?
도널드는 다른 고객들처럼
Donald introduced him
그를 소개했어요
as another client.
그 사람 예술계와
관련된 일을 했던가 싶은데
Uh... I think he had something
to do with the art world.
사실 그 사람, 그날밤
In fact, he donated
a few paintings
경매에 그림 몇 점도
기부했어요
to the auction
that night.
다 팔렸던 걸로 알고 있어요
I'm pretty sure
they all sold.
고맙습니다,
많은 도움 되었습니다
Thank you. This
was very helpful.
매덕스가 예술계에 몸담고 있는
He said Maddox
was a client of Hauser's
하우저의 고객이라고는 하지만
who was involved
in the art world.
제가 그 고객명단 다
뒤진 자료에서--
I have been all over
that client list--
이에 근접한 유일한 곳이
첼시에 있는 아트갤러리에요
the only thing that comes close
is an art gallery in Chelsea.
매덕스 이름하고 그쪽은 결부
된 게 없었어요
Maddox's name was not
associated with it.
그가 익명의 동업자일 수도
있다는 생각 안 들어요?
But do you think he may
have been a silent partner?
그럼, 그가 기부한 예술품이 어디서
났는지 설명이 되겠군요
Well, it would explain where
he got all the art he donated.
죄송한데, 음..
Sorry, mm...
몰라요
이 사람 모른다고요?
no.
You don't know him?
으-음.
Mm-mm.
파비아나
그런 이름이셨죠?
Fabiana,
did you say it was?
파비아나, 당신이
이 시설 소유주가
Fabiana, would it
be safe to assume
아니라고 추정해도
무방하지 않을까 하는데?
that you are not the owner
of this establishment?
왜 그런 추정을 하세요?
Why you assume that?
결례를 범할 뜻은 없었어요
I mean no disrespect.
틀림없이 이 조직의 소중한
직원이실 터이니
I'm sure you're a valued
member of the team.
주인 혹은 주인들을 잘 아시죠?
But do you know
the owner, or owners?
물론이죠
Of course.
하지만 사진 속 남자는 모르고
But you don't know
the man in the photograph.
넬슨 매덕스라는 이름은
금시초문이라고요?
And the name Nelson Maddox
doesn't mean anything to you?
예, 죄송해요
No. Sorry.
구경하며 둘러봐도
Uh, do you mind
괜찮겠지요?
if we peruse?
신-탈개념주의파의
엄청난 팬이라서
Huge fans of
the neo-deconceptualists.
그러세요
Sure.
고맙습니다
Thank you.
신-탈개념주의파요?
Neo-deconceptualists?
말도 안 돼
Not a thing.
파비아나에게 이르지 마요--
좌절할 지도 모르니
Don't tell Fabiana--
it might crush her.
그러니 넬슨을 모른다고
So she was
obviously lying
대놓고 거짓말을 하는군요
about not knowing
Nelson Maddox.
그래요, 대놓고
Yeah, obviously.
(-)
잠깐만요
Excuse me.
뭔가 보여요?
You see something?
파비아나, 오늘 아침 갤러리 문
당신이 열었어요?
Fabiana, did you open up
the gallery this morning?
그래요
Yeah.
이상한 점 없었어요?
Nothing out
of the ordinary?
예
No.
예라
바닥이 뒤꿈치로 긁혔어요
Heel scuffs on the floor.
예
Yeah.
누군가 끌고 간것처럼
Looks like
someone was dragged.
이쪽 바깥으로
Out here.
(-)
♪
당신 대답을 개정하시겠어요?
Would you care to
revise your answers?
넬슨 매덕과 이 갤러리와
Because it would appear
모종의 관계가 있다는 점이
that Nelson Maddox
has some connection
어쨌거나 곧 드러날 테니
to this gallery after all.
매덕스의 차가
So, Maddox's car
한 블럭 위에 주차되었고
그 안에서
was parked up the block,
and inside it,
구경이 들어맞는 총하고,
도널드 하우저와 로잘리 누녜즈를
we found the gun,
right caliber, and the same
묶는 데 사용한 것과
동일한 밧줄을 발견했어
kind of rope used to bind
Donald Hauser and Rosalie Nunez.
상황이 이렇다 보니
파비아나는 매덕스가
Now, under the circumstances,
Fabiana admitted
익명의 동업자라고 인정했고
that Maddox was
a silent partner, and
그의 전문적인 직업은
불법마약을 분별 깊은
that his main line of work
was distributing street drugs
수준의 고객들에게 배부하는
일이라고 털어 놨어
to a discreet level
of clientele.
그와 같이, 부자들을 위한
딜러 역할도
As in, a dealer
for rich people.
아마도 고용주들은
투자자로 마약판매상이 있다고
Presumably, her employers
were not fond of admitting
인정하는 일을 곱게 볼리 없으니
they had a drug dealer
as an investor.
처음에 입다물었겠죠
Hence, her
initial silence.
그러니 매덕스 돈은
갤러리에 묶여있고
So Maddox had money tied up
in the gallery,
갤러리는 도널드 하우저의
고객이었어
and the gallery was a client
of Donald Hauser's.
그걸로 매덕스가 하우저를
죽인 이유로 설명이 돼
So, that explains
why Maddox killed Hauser.
이제 질문은, 누가 매덕스를
죽였느냐?
Now, the question is,
who killed Maddox?
그리고 왜 매덕스가
로잘리 누녜즈를 죽이고
And why did Maddox
kill Rosalie Nunez and
노트북을 훔쳤는가에요
steal her laptop?
분명 하우저 다단계 사기를
She must have found something
조사하다가 매덕스에 관해
알아냈을 거예요
on Maddox when she researched
Hauser's pyramid scam.
하지만 하우저와의 연관이
오직 이 갤러리 뿐이라면
But if his only
connection to Hauser
어쩌다가 그런 일에
유죄 입증에 연루 시켰을까요?
was this gallery, what's so
incriminating about that?
왓슨, 당신 생각이 맞아요
Watson, I think you're right.
뭐가 맞아요?
About what?
로잘리 누녜즈는 이 갤러리가
That Rosalie Nunez knew
겉보기와는 다른 무언가
있는 줄 알았어요
that there was more to this
gallery than meets the eye.
붉은 점이 벽 위에
The red dots
몇몇 작품 옆에
on the wall
that are placed next
붙어 있는데
to some of the pieces.
이와 유사한 기관에서
볼 수 있는 것처럼,
As you would find
in any such establishment,
점 찍힌 품목은 팔렸다는
they're placed next
to an item to indicate
표식으로 보통 붙여 놓죠
that that particular item
has been sold.
하지만 이 갤러리에서는...
But in this gallery...
그 점이 일정하게 매 세번째
작품마다 붙어있어요
the dots are consistently placed
next to every third piece.
마치 어느 한 사람이
As if a single individual,
비교적 일정한 발걸음으로
방을 돌아 걸어가며,
walking at a relatively
steady pace, circled the room,
붉은 표를 하나씩 뜯어내 ...
peeling off dots...
특정 작품이 팔린 표시를
randomly designating
무작위로 지정한것처럼
certain pieces as sold.
현실은 이렇게 깔끔하지 않아요
Reality would never be so tidy.
여기 보이는 바는 조악하게
이행한 거짓말이에요
What we have here
is a shoddily executed lie.
이런 점들은
I submit that these dots
사업이 이뤄지고 있다는
것처럼 보이려고
exist to make
it look like
존재했다는 의견입니다
business is being
conducted in here.
그런 까닭에, 실은 우리가
발딛고 서 있는 갤러리는
Whereas, in truth,
the gallery in which we stand
돈세탁을 위한 위장일 가능성이
아주 높습니다
is much more likely
a money-laundering front.
.
파비아나?
Fabiana?
한 가지 더 부탁드려도?
장부요
Can I trouble you
for one more thing? Your books.
벽에 걸린 이들 작품이
진짜로 팔렸다면
If these items on the walls
have indeed been sold,
누구에게 팔렸는지 그
기록을 보관하고 있겠지요?
you must maintain a record of
whom they've been sold to, yes?
예
Yes.
절 보자고요?
You wanted to see me?
제이콥 와이스 이쪽은
NYPD 그렉슨 반장님이십니다
Jacob Weiss, this is
Captain Gregson of the NYPD.
안녕하세요?
How do you do?
하신 일 정말 출중합니다
Magnificent work you do.
수십년 전 그런 끔찍한
잘못을 아주 자그마나
Setting right, in at
least some small way,
적어도 바로 잡으려하시다니
such a horrific wrong
done decades ago.
이 홀로코스터 생존자들은
어떻게 느끼실지 궁금하네요
I wonder how some of the
Holocaust survivors would feel,
그 사람들이 알지도 모른 새,
아 아니, 한 푼 보지 못했는데
knowing that money had
been claimed in their names
그들 이름으로 배상금이
청구되는지 알면-
without them knowing,
or-or even seeing a dime.
뭐라는 겁니까?
Excuse me?
당신은 이미 죽거나
You've been embezzling millions
한번도 통고를 못 받은
생존자들의 이름으로
from your own
charity by filing
가짜 청구서를 제출하여
false claims
in the names of survivors
자선단체에서
수백만을 횡령했습니다
who are either dead, or who were
simply never informed.
어떻게 감히 그런 혐의를...?!
How-how dare you accuse me...?!
여기 이 명단은
넬슨 매덕스 갤러리에서
This is a list of people
예술작품을 구매한 것으로
추정되는 명단입니다
who supposedly bought artwork
from Nelson Maddox's gallery.
당신이 전혀 아는 바
없다고 주장했던
The same gallery
that you claimed
갤러리과 동일한 갤러립니다
to know absolutely
nothing about.
웃기는 일은
Funny thing is,
이 이름들 모두 전에 어디 다른
데서 본 기억이 난다 이겁니다
I remember seeing all of
these names somewhere before.
여기, 조각상에서요
Here, on this
sculpture.
엄청난 우연의 일치 아닙니까?
It's quite a
coincidence, isn't it?
어찌 이리 많은
갤러리 고객들이
So many of the
gallery's customers
하필 또 당신이 도운
생존자들이라니
being survivors
that you'd helped.
당신과 매덕스는
사업 파트너였어요
You and Nelson Maddox
were business partners.
당신은 횡령한 돈을
갤러리를 통해 세탁했어요
You laundered the embezzled
money through his gallery.
그게 도날드 하우저 파일에
That was
the incriminating evidence
있던 유죄 입증 증거였어요
in Donald Hauser's files.
자선단체의 공인회개사로서,
We strongly suspect
하우저는 무슨 일이
진행되는지 깨닫고
that, as the
charity's CPA,
그라도 이는 참고 묵과할 수
Hauser realized what was
going on, and even he
없지 않았을까 합니다
couldn't stomach it.
자신이 세운 엉성한 구조물이
When his own
house of cards
무너져 내리자
came tumbling down,
목숨을 버리기로 결심합니다
and he decided
to take his own life,
그리고 당신의 계략에 대해
알고 있는 바를
he also decided
to share what he knew
로잘리 누녜즈와 공유하기로도
결심하지요
about your scheme
with Rosalie Nunez.
당신의 말마따나
In your own words,
아마 업보의 평행추였겠죠
perhaps it was
a "karmic counterbalance."
실수로 당신에게 주의를
주지 않았을까 생각합니다
We think his mistake was
giving you a heads-up.
아마도 며칠 전 둘이서
저녁을 먹으면서였겠죠
Probably when the two of you
had dinner a few nights ago.
시간을 벌어 매덕스와
접촉을 하고, 그는
That gave you time to contact
Maddox, who then tortured
그 파일을 어떻게 했는지
알아 내려고 고문을 했어요
out of Hauser
what he'd done with the files.
매덕스 그런 뒤 로잘리를
줄이고 노트북을 가져가요
Maddox then killed Rosalie,
and took her laptop.
우리가 매덕스를 살인범으로
When you saw on
the news that we had
확인했다는 뉴스를 보자
identified Maddox as the killer,
흔적을 지우려고 그를 죽였어요
you killed him
to cover your tracks.
이미 이른바 구매객의 명단을
We're already working
our way down
조사를 착착 진행중입니다
that list
of supposed art buyers.
지금까지, 가족이나 본인
누구도 여섯자리 숫자
So far, not one of them
or their families had any idea
합의금을 지급
받은 적이 없답니다
they'd been awarded
six-figure settlements.
당신이 왜 그런지
I don't suppose you'd like
해명할 성 싶지도 않구요
to explain
why that is.
오, 죄송합니다. 저는...
Oh, sorry. I was, uh...
그렉슨 반장님 찾고 있었습니다
I was looking
for Captain Gregson.
벨 형사
Detective Bell.
괜찮아, 들어와
That's all right.
Come in.
프랭크 다 실
Frank Da Silva.
앉으시게
Have a seat.
그러니까
다 실바 부청장님?
As in,
Deputy Commissioner Da Silva?
그렉슨 반장은 마음이
좋아서 우리가 사적으로
Captain Gregson was nice enough
to lend us his office
이야기를 나누라고 사무실을
빌려줬어
so that we could
speak privately.
내 부서에 대해 무얼
알고 있나, 형사?
What do you know
about my division, Detective?
알만큼 알죠
I got a pretty
good idea.
정보국을 책임지고 계시지요?
감시 같은?
You're in charge of an
intelligence unit? Surveillance?
통계국이라고 불러
It's called
the Demographics Unit.
-
내가 고른 이름 아냐
The-the name's not mine.
내 보기에 너무
완곡한 표현이야-
To me, uh,
being so euphemistic--
그래 놓으니 도리어 무언가 잘못된
일을 벌이고 있는 것처럼 들리잖아
it's, um, makes it sound like
you're doing something wrong.
우리는 안 그런데
And we're not.
우리는 그냥...
We're just...
특정 그룹을 계속 주시를
하고 있는 거지
keeping an eye out
on certain groups.
관심 가는 잡담이라도
나누나 듣기도 하고
Listening
for concerning chatter.
자네가 우리가 무슨 일을
I think if you took
했나 가까이 살피면
a close look
at what we've been doing,
우리가 시를 안전하게 유지하고
있다는 데 동의하리라 믿네
you'd agree that
we're keeping the city safe.
저 납득시키실 필요없...
You don't have
to convince me...
-아니네, 납득시키고 싶다네
-네?
No, but I'd like to.
Sir?
자네하고 이야기 나누고 싶었어
I wanted to talk to you
자네 상황이 내 관심을 끌어서
because your situation has been
brought to my attention.
자네 특출한 요원이라고 들었어
I'm told that you are
an exceptional detective.
자네는 어깨 위에 좋은 머리를
얹은 사내지
You're a man with a good head
on his shoulders,
그 자신의 잘못도 아니고
who, by no fault of his own,
상당히 오랫동안, 사무적인 일만
may be staring at a desk job
잔뜩 쏘아보고 있어야 하고,
for a good, long time.
아니면...
Or...
내 밑에서 일을 해도 되지
you could come work for me.
흥미가 돋나, 형사?
Does that interest you,
Detective?
자네 뉴욕시를 다음 공격에
보호할 마음 있는가?
Would you care to help protect
your city from the next attack?
(-)
-
들어, 오시오!
Enter!
랜덜, 와줘서 고마워요
Randall, thank you for coming.
뭐
Sure.
집 멋지네요
Cool place.
앉으시겠어요?
Won't you please sit down?
이봐요...
Look, man...
후견인되고 싶지 않아도
문제 없어요
if you don't want
to be my sponsor, it's all good.
합니다
I do.
제가 하지요
내가 알프레도를 후견인으로
골랐을 때, 충동적으로 그랬어요
When I chose Alfredo to be
my sponsor, I did so on a whim.
누군가 찾아야 한다는 압박이
느껴져 마구잡이로 골랐죠
I felt pressure to find one,
so I chose him at random.
나는 그 사람 기대치가
아주 낮았고,
I had very low expectations
of him,
후원관계도, 대체로 별 기대
없었어요
and of sponsorship, in general.
나는 둘 다 필요없다고 생각했어요
Didn't think
I needed either.
제가 틀렸어요
I was wrong.
그는 프로그램에서 가장 좋은
점을 뽑아내는 법을 가르쳤어요
He has taught me how to get the
very most out of the program.
나를 오냐오냐 받아주지도 않았고
He did not coddle me.
그러니, 우리가 우리의 관계를
공식화하기로 선택한다면
And so, if we choose
to formalize our relationship,
저 역시 응석
받아주지는 않습니다
I will not coddle you.
당신이 친구를 찾아
여기 온 거라면
If you have come
seeking a friend,
다른 데서 찾아보세요
look elsewhere.
치료사가 필요하면
If you need a therapist,
흔쾌히 그런 이들의 명단을
건네드리겠습니다
I will happily supply you
with a list.
저는 오로지 당신 후견인
역할만 할 겁니다
I will only ever be
your sponsor.
당신과 내 방법들을
공유할 것이고
I will share
with you my methods,
끊는 일에 헌신이 저만큼
대단하기를 바랍니다
and hope that your commitment to
sobriety is as great as my own.
이런 조건들 수락하십니까?
Are these terms acceptable?
당신은 중독을 벗었어요
You're sober.
지금까지 오랫동안
그렇게 유지하고 있어요
You have been
for a long time now.
그런 조건
당연히 수락합니다
Of course
I find the terms acceptable.